Guide to the University Council, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
University Council, Yale University, records
1948-2008
RU 782
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.25
(15 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, reports and committee files documenting the activities and operations of the University Council.
Yale University Council
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 1-C (YRG 1-C), Records of Yale University advisory groups.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
The University Council serves as an advisory group to the University. Its committees study various needs and areas of the University and submit reports for consideration by the President and Yale Corporation.
The University Council may be composed of a maximum of thirty-five members appointed by the Corporation on nomination by the President and, as ex officio representatives, the Chairman of the Association of Yale Alumni and the Chairman of the Alumni Fund. Members serve for terms of up to five years, as designated by the President, and elect their own President annually.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, reports and committee files documenting the activities and operations of the University Council.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University Council
- Records concerning University Council committees, 1968-1988; Accession 1991-A-076
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2023
  - Art School, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art Gallery and British Art Center, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art Gallery and British Art Center, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Community Relations, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Divinity School, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Drama School, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Forestry and Environmental Studies, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Graduate School, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Graduate School, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9A)
  - Humanities--Historical, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Humanities--historical, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Humanities--literature, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Law School, 1970-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Library, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Library, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Medical Affairs, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Medical Affairs, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Medical Affairs, 1968-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Music, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Music, 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Music, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Peabody Museum, 1970-1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Physical Sciences and Engineering, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - School of Organization and Management (SOM), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - School of Organization and Management (SOM), 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Sciences--Biological, 1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Sciences--Physical, 1973-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Social Sciences--Behavioral, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Social Sciences--Behavioral, 1971-1982 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Social Sciences--Behavioral, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sccial Sciences--Policy, 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sccial Sciences--Policy, 1974-1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Yale College, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Yale College, 1972-1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Urifversity Council Directories - Past, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - University Council - AYA, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Reports of the University Council, 1948-1980; Accession 1991-A-097
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged chronologically.
  The materials are open for research.
  - Reports (bound)
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1948-1949
    - 1949-1950
    - 1950-1951
    - 1951-1952
    - 1952-1953
    - 1953-1954
    - 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - 1955-1956
    - 1956-1957
    - 1957-1958
    - 1958-1959
    - 1959-1960
    - 1960-1961
    - 1961-1962
    - 1962-1963 (Box 3)
    - 1963-1964
    - 1964-1965
    - 1965-1966
    - 1966-1967
    - 1967-1968
    - 1968-1969
    - 1970 (Box 4)
    - 1970-1971
    - 1971-1972
    - 1972-1973
    - 1973-1974
    - 1974-1975
    - 1975-1976
    - 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - 1977-1978
    - 1978-1979
    - 1979-1980
- University Council Committee reports, 1980-1991; Accession 1992-A-051
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2026
  - Administrative Computing at Yale, Informal Study: Final Report, 1983 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Architecture, Committee on the School of: Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art, Committee on the School of
    - Interim Report, 1989 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Final Report, 199? April 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Art Gallery and Bristol Art Center, Committee on
    - Final Report, 198? April 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Final Report, 1983 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Final Report, 1983 April 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Interim Report, 1991 December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Athletics, Committee on
    - Final Report, 1980 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Interim Report, 1985 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Final Report, 1987 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Biological Sciences, Committee on
    - Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Interim Report, 1983 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Interim Report, 1991 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Communications, Committee on
    - Interim Report, 1985 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Final Report, 1990 March (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Community Relations Committee, 1981 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Divinity School, Committee on the
    - Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Final Report, 1982 November (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Interim Report, 1985 November (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Divinity School, Committee on the
    - Final Report, 1988 April (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Final Report, 1988 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Drama, Committee on
    - Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Interim Report, 1989 December (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Energy Management Program, Report, 1983 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Forestry and Environmental Studies, Committee on the School of: Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Graduate School, Committee on the
    - Interim Report, 1983 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Final Report, 1985 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Interim Report, 1990 December 7 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Humanities-Foreign Language and Area Studies, Committee on (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Final Report, 1978 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Humanities-Historical, Committee on: Preliminary Report, 1984 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Humanities-Literature, Committee on
    - Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Interim Report, 1988 December (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Final Report, 1989 December (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - History, The Committee on Departments and Programs Involving: Interim Report, 1990 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - The institute of Sacred Music, Committee on
    - Interim Report, 1987 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Final Report, 1988 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Law School, Committee on the
    - Final Report, 1980 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Final Report, 1983 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Interim Report, 1986 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Final Report, 1988 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Library, Committee on the
    - Final Report, 1981 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Final Report, 1983 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Final Report, 1986 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Final Report, 1988 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Preliminary Report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Medical Affairs, Committee on
    - Final Report, 1980 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Final Report, 1983 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Final Report, 1985 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Final Report, 1985 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Final Report, 1986 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Interim Report, 1990 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Minutes of the Spring Meeting, 1986 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Music, Committee on
    - Interim Report, 1986 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Final Report, 1988 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Organization and Management, Committee on the School of
    - [blank], Circa 1985 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Final Report, 1988 May (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - The Peabody Meseum, Committee on
    - Preliminary Report, 1987 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Final Report, 1989 December (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Physical Sciences and Engineering, Committee on
    - [blank], 1986 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Special Report on Engineering, 1989 December 15 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Special Report on Engineering, Revised, 1991 March (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Religious Life, Committee on: Final Report, 1990 April (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Social Sciences (Behavioral), Committee on the
    - Interim Report, 1984 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Final Report, 1986 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Interim Report, 1990 December 7 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Social Sciences-Policy, Committee on
    - Preliminary Draft, 1988 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Interim Report, Undated (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Writing, Committee on: Interim Report, 1987 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Yale College Committee: Interim Report, 1989 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- University Council Committee on Diversification records, 2005-2007; Accession 2008-A-124
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2042
  - Correspondence, minutes, reports, and memoranda, 2005-2007 (Box 1)
- University Council committee materials, 1948-2008; Accession 2012-A-022
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2043
  - AYA Report & Correspondence, 1973 August (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - List of Awards, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership Directory, 1987 - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership Directory, 1988 - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Directory, 1989 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Members Certificate/Letters of Appreciation, 1979-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971 - 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Executive Committee, 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Speech by President A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1978 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - UCC Editorials, Articles, 1948-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - UCC History, Background, 1974, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - UCC List of Members, 1973 - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - UCC List of Members, 1989 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - UCC List of Members, 1990 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - UCC List of Members, 1991 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - UCC List of Members, 1992 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - UCC List of Members, 1994 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - UCC Officers & Administrators, 1990 - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - UCC Report History, 1948-1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - UCC Sub-Committee Members, 1990 - 2008 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - University Council 40th Anniversary, 1988 August (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - University Council Committee Scrapbook, 1948 - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - University Council Committee on Physical Sciences and Engineering, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - University Council Reports & Responses, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - University Council Reports & Responses, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - University Council Update, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - University Council Update, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- University Council records, 1983-2002; Accession 2014-A-025
  Restricted until January 1, 2037
  - General
    - University Council re-structuring memoranda, 1993 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committees
    - Architecture, School of, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - Art Gallery and British Art Center, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Art, School of, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
    - Athletics, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Clinical Initiatives, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - Development, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
    - Distance Learning, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - Forestry and Environmental Studies, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - History, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Information Technology, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21-26)
    - Law, School of, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Library, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Medical Affairs, 1983, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
    - Music, School of, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Nursing, School of, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 32-35)
    - Peabody Museum, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Physical Sciences and Engineering, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Social Sciences-policy, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Technology and Learning, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Meetings
    - 1988 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 1989 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 1989 November 30-December 1 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 1990 April 26-27 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - 1990 December 6-7 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - 1991 April 18-19 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - 1991 December 5-6 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - 1992 April 23-24 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - 1992 December 3-4 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - 1993 April 29-30 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - 1993 December 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - 1994 April 7-8 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - 1994 December 1-2 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - 1995 April 6-7 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - 1995 December 7-8 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - 1996 May 2-3 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - 1996 December 12-13 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - 1997 April 17-18 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - 1997 December 11-12 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - 1998 April 30-May 1 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - 1998 December 10-11 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - 1999 April 30 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - 1999 December 5-6 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - 2000 June 4-5 (Box 3, Folder 63)